Eliane Fortes | Software Engineer

Melbourne - Australia • 0405 097 837

<u>elimrfortes@gmail.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/eliane-fortes</u> • <u>github.com/elifortes</u>



PROFILE

Passionate Software Engineer with a foundation in full-stack development and a background in business analysis and customer service. Experienced in creating innovative, user-focused solutions with a demonstrated ability to work collaboratively. Graduated in Business Administration with advanced analytical skills from a Data Analytics course. When not improving my skills, I enjoy walking with my dog or playing tennis.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- Bootstrap
- React.js
- Node.js
- Express.js
- SQL
- GitHub
- Heroku
- Customer Service
- Jira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SUPPORT WORKER | DISCOVER NURSING AUSTRALIA, SYDNEY

Jan 2018 - Aug 2023

- Provided customer service, emphasizing empathy, and understanding.
- Addressed and resolved client queries effectively, indicating strong problem-solving skills and customer-focused service.
- Coordinated care consultations, reflecting excellent organizational and timemanagement abilities.

BUSINESS ANALYST | VALEO THERMAL BUS SYSTEMS, CAXIAS DO SUL/BRAZIL

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017

- Conducted regular statistical report generation, emphasizing analytical skills and attention to detail.
- Analysis and negotiation of orders and delivery schedules with customers.
- Responsible for monitoring daily revenue and meeting targets.
- Participation in the qualification of processes, identifying and applying innovations and differentiated solutions, and validating the applicability of new technologies, knowledge, and practices.

BUSINESS ANALYST | KEKO, CAXIAS DO SUL/BRAZIL

Feb 2012 - May 2016

- Conducted regular statistical report generation, emphasizing analytical skills and attention to detail.
- Analysis and negotiation of orders and delivery schedules with customers.
- Responsible for monitoring daily revenue and meeting targets.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP | LE WAGON, MELBOURNE

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Completed a 9-week full-time intensive coding bootcamp.
- Applied practical knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.
- Developed and Airbnb-inspired boat rental platform.
- Proposed and developed the web app Gift Genius, completing the project within 2 weeks as part of a 3-person team.

THE ULTIMATE IT BEGINNERS - FROM 0 TO JUNIOR ENGINEER | TECHWORLD WITH NANA Sep 2023 – Sep 2023

- Gained hands-on experience in the full Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), enhancing understanding of software development and release workflows.
- Developed a simple web application integrating frontend, backend, and database using a comprehensive tech stack including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Acquired foundational knowledge in infrastructure management, including virtual server creation and configuration on cloud platforms.

DATA ANALYTICS BOOTCAMP | GENERAL ASSEMBLY, SYDNEY

Apr 2022 – Jul 2022

- Applied practical knowledge of Tableau, PostgreSQL, and Excel.
- Delivered a project analysing Chicago City Council phone requests and provide a detailed examination of complaints by the councilperson elected to represent the area.

BACHELOR OF MANAGEMENT ADMINISTRATION | UCS, CAXIAS DO SUL/BRAZIL

Mar 2010 - Jul 2017